<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FrameList>
	<frame>
		<name>Loss of recent memory after bilateral hippocampal lesions</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Scoville, William Beecher</rsc>
			<rsc>Milner, Brendad</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1957</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Everything</fcs>
			<fcs>Memory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			In 1954 Scoville described a grave loss of recent memory
			which he had observed as a sequel to bilateral medial
			temporal lobe resection in one psychotic patient and one
			patient with intractable seizures. In both cases the opera-
			tions  had  been  radical  ones,  undertaken  only  when
			more  conservative  forms  of  treatment  had  failed.  The
			removals extended posteriorly along the mesial surface
			of the temporal lobes for a distance of approximately 8
			cm from the temporal tips and probably destroyed the
			anterior two-thirds of the hippocampus and hippocam-
			pal gyrus bilaterally, as well as the uncus and amygdala.
			The  unexpected  and  persistent  memory  deÆcit  which
			resulted seemed to us to merit further investigation. We
			have  therefore  carried out  formal  memory and  intelli-
			gence  testing  of  these  two  patients  and  also  of  eight
			other patients who had undergone similar, but less rad-
			ical, bilateral medial temporal lobe resections. The pres-
			ent paper gives the results of these studies which point
			to the importance of the hippocampal complex for nor-
			mal memory function. Whenever the hippocampus and
			hippocampal  gyrus  were  damaged  bilaterally  in  these
			operations some memory deÆcit was found, but not oth-
			erwise. We have chosen to report these Ændings in full,
			partly for their theoretical signiÆcance, and partly as a
			warning  to  others  of  the  risk  to  memory  involved  in bilateral
			surgical lesions of the hippocampal region.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Evolutionary Anorexia</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Mrosovsky</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2004</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Bilogical Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Evolutionary psychology</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>STUDY NOT FOUND</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>PET evalutaion of bilingual language compensation following early childhood brain damage</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Tierney, Michael C</rsc>
			<rsc>Varga, Mary</rsc>
			<rsc>Hosey, Lara</rsc>
			<rsc>Grafman, Jordan</rsc>
			<rsc>Braun, Allen</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2001</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Biological Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Localization of Function</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			We report a positron emission tomography (PET) study in a
			37-year-old, right handed, bilingual (English and American Sign
			Language) male with left frontal lobe damage, without evidence of
			language or general intellectual dysfunction. A brain MRI scan
			demonstrated an atrophic lesion of the left dorsolateral prefrontal,
			orbital, and opercular cortices extending from the frontal pole to
			precentral gyrus and including parts of anterior cingulate cortex,
			due to an probable infantile encephalitis. H215O PET scans found
			evidence of increased right hemisphere activity compared to normal
			controls during spontaneous generation of narrative in both English
			and ASL. Neuropsychological data were within normal limits with the
			exception of visuospatial function. The results suggest the possibility
			that plasticity, unmasking of neural pathways, and or other
			adaptations of language function in the right hemisphere may have
			occurred, and are discussed with regard to the crowding hypothesis.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Neuroplasticity: Changes in grey matter induced by training</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Draganski, Bogdan</rsc>
			<rsc>Gaser, Christian</rsc>
			<rsc>Bogdahn, Ulrich</rsc>
			<rsc>May, Arne</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2004</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Biological Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Imaging technology</fcs>
			<fcs>Localization of Function</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>ABSTRACT NOT FOUND</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Brain changes in response to experience</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Rosenwig, Mark R</rsc>
			<rsc>Bennet, Edward L</rsc>
			<rsc>Diamond, Marian C</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1972</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Biological Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Localization of Function</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Reports a study in which rats placed in enriched or
			impoverished environments for 4-10 wk. differed in brain anatomy and
			chemistry. Ss with enriched experience had heavier and thicker
			cerebral cortexes, greater total activity of acetylcholinesterase
			but less activity per unit of tissue weight, greater activity of
			cholinesterase, more glial cells, larger cell bodies and nuclei,
			more dendritic spines, larger synaptic junctions, and increased
			RNA/DNA ratios. The greatest differences were found in the occipital
			cortex. It is suggested that daily 2-hr enrichment periods may be
			effective if the rat is stimulated to interact with objects in the
			environment. Changes were not caused by variations in amount of
			handling, stress, or maturation rate.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Oxytocin modulates neural circuitry for social cognition and fear in humans</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Kirch, Peter</rsc>
			<rsc>Esslinger, Christine</rsc>
			<rsc>Chen, Quiang</rsc>
			<rsc>Mier, Daniela</rsc>
			<rsc>Lis, Stefanie</rsc>
			<rsc>Siddhanti, Sarina</rsc>
			<rsc>Gruppe, Harald</rsc>
			<rsc>Mattay, Venkata S.</rsc>
			<rsc>Gallhofer, Bernd</rsc>
			<rsc>Meyer-Lindenberg, Andreas</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2005</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Biological Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Neurotransmission</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			In non-human mammals, the neuropeptide oxytocin is a key
			mediator of complex emotional and social behaviors, including
			attachment, social recognition, and aggression. Oxytocin reduces
			anxiety and impacts on fear conditioning and extinction. Recently,
			oxytocin administration in humans was shown to increase trust,
			suggesting involvement of the amygdala, a central component of the
			neurocircuitry of fear and social cognition that has been linked to
			trust and highly expresses oxytocin receptors in many mammals.
			However, no human data on the effects of this peptide on brain
			function were available. Here, we show that human amygdala function
			is strongly modulated by oxytocin. We used functional magnetic
			resonance imaging to image amygdala activation by fear-inducing
			visual stimuli in 15 healthy males after double-blind crossover
			intranasal application of placebo or oxytocin. Compared with
			placebo, oxytocin potently reduced activation of the amygdala and
			reduced coupling of the amygdala to brainstem regions implicated in
			autonomic and behavioral manifestations of fear. Our results
			indicate a neural mechanism for the effects of oxytocin in social
			cognition in the human brain and provide a methodology and rationale
			for exploring therapeutic strategies in disorders in which abnormal
			amygdala function has been implicated, such as social phobia or
			autism.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Light from self luminous tablet computers can affect melatonin</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Figuerio, Mariana G</rsc>
			<rsc>Wood, Brittany</rsc>
			<rsc>Rea, Mark S</rsc>
			<rsc>Plitnick, Barbara</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2012</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Biological Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Neurotransmission</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Exposure to light from self-luminous displays may be linked to
			increased risk for sleep disorders because these devices emit
			optical radiation at short wavelengths, close to the peak
			sensitivity of melatonin suppression. Thirteen participants
			experienced three experimental conditions in a within-subjects
			design to investigate the impact of self-luminous tablet displays on
			nocturnal melatonin suppression: 1) tablets-only set to the highest
			brightness, 2) tablets viewed through clear-lens goggles equipped
			with blue light-emitting diodes that provided 40 lux of 470-nm light
			at the cornea, and 3) tablets viewed through orange-tinted glasses
			(dark control; optical radiation &lt;525 nm ≈ 0). Melatonin
			suppressions after 1-h and 2-h exposures to tablets viewed with the
			blue light were significantly greater than zero. Suppression levels
			after 1-h exposure to the tablets-only were not statistically
			different than zero; however, this difference reached significance
			after 2 h. Based on these results, display manufacturers can
			determine how their products will affect melatonin levels and use
			model predictions to tune the spectral power distribution of
			self-luminous devices to increase or to decrease stimulation to the
			circadian system.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Role of genotype in the cycle of violence in maltreated children</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Caspi, Avshalom</rsc>
			<rsc>McClay, Joseph</rsc>
			<rsc>Moffitt, Terrie E</rsc>
			<rsc>Mill, Jonathan</rsc>
			<rsc>Martin, Judy</rsc>
			<rsc>Craig, Ian W</rsc>
			<rsc>Taylor, Alan</rsc>
			<rsc>Poulton, Richie</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2002</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Biological Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Genetics</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			We studied a large sample of male children from birth to
			adulthood to determine why some children who are maltreated grow up
			to develop antisocial behavior, whereas others do not. A functional
			polymorphism in the gene encoding the neurotransmitter-metabolizing
			enzyme monoamine oxidase A (MAOA) was found to moderate the effect
			of maltreatment. Maltreated children with a genotype conferring high
			levels of MAOA expression were less likely to develop antisocial
			problems. These findings may partly explain why not all victims of
			maltreatment grow up to victimize others, and they provide
			epidemiological evidence that genotypes can moderate children's
			sensitivity to environmental insults.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Influence of life stress on depression: moderation by a polymorphism of the 5-HTT gene</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Caspi, Avshalom</rsc>
			<rsc>Sugden, K</rsc>
			<rsc>Moffitt, TE</rsc>
			<rsc>Taylor, A</rsc>
			<rsc>Craig, IW</rsc>
			<rsc>Harrington, H</rsc>
			<rsc>McClay, J</rsc>
			<rsc>Mill, J</rsc>
			<rsc>Martin, J</rsc>
			<rsc>Braithwaite, A</rsc>
			<rsc>Poulton, R</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2003</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Biological Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Genetics</fcs>
			<fcs>Depression</fcs>
			<fcs>Abnormal psychology</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			In a prospective-longitudinal study of a representative birth
			cohort, we tested why stressful experiences lead to depression in
			some people but not in others. A functional polymorphism in the
			promoter region of the serotonin transporter (5-HT T) gene was found
			to moderate the influence of stressful life events on depression.
			Individuals with one or two copies of the short allele of the 5-HT T
			promoter polymorphism exhibited more depressive symptoms,
			diagnosable depression, and suicidality in relation to stressful
			life events than individuals homozygous for the long allele. This
			epidemiological study thus provides evidence of a
			gene-by-environment interaction, in which an individual's response
			to environmental insults is moderated by his or her genetic makeup.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Romantic love: a mammalian brain system for mate choice</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Fisher, Helen E</rsc>
			<rsc>Aron, Arthur</rsc>
			<rsc>Brown, Lucy L</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2006</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Biological Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Imaging</fcs>
			<fcs>Localization of Function</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Mammals and birds regularly express mate preferences and make
			mate choices. Data on mate choice among mammals suggest that this
			behavioural ‘attraction system’ is associated with dopaminergic
			reward pathways in the brain. It has been proposed that intense
			romantic love, a human cross-cultural universal, is a developed form
			of this attraction system. To begin to determine the neural
			mechanisms associated with romantic attraction in humans, we used
			functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) to study 17 people who
			were intensely ‘in love’. Activation specific to the beloved
			occurred in the brainstem right ventral tegmental area and right
			postero-dorsal body of the caudate nucleus. These and other results
			suggest that dopaminergic reward and motivation pathways contribute
			to aspects of romantic love. We also used fMRI to study 15 men and
			women who had just been rejected in love. Preliminary analysis
			showed activity specific to the beloved in related regions of the
			reward system associated with monetary gambling for uncertain large
			gains and losses, and in regions of the lateral orbitofrontal cortex
			 associated with theory of mind, obsessive/compulsive behaviours and
			controlling anger. These data contribute to our view that romantic
			love is one of the three primary brain systems that evolved in
			avian and mammalian species to direct reproduction. The sex drive
			evolved to motivate individuals to seek a range of mating partners;
			attraction evolved to motivate individuals to prefer and pursue
			specific partners; and attachment evolved to motivate individuals to
			remain together long enough to complete species-specific parenting
			duties. These three behavioural repertoires appear to be based on
			brain systems that are largely distinct yet interrelated, and they
			interact in specific ways to orchestrate reproduction, using both
			hormones and monoamines. Romantic attraction in humans and its
			antecedent in other mammalian species play a primary role: this
			neural mechanism motivates individuals to focus their courtship
			energy on specific others, thereby conserving valuable time and
			metabolic energy, and facilitating mate choice.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Social categorization and intergroup behavior [The minimal group paradigm]</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Tajfel, Henri</rsc>
			<rsc>Billig, MG</rsc>
			<rsc>Bundy, RP</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1971</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Social Identity Theory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			The aim of the studies was to assess the effects of social
			categorization on intergroup behavior when, in the intergroup situation,
			neither calculations of individual interest nor previously existing
			attitudes of hostility could have been said to have determined
			discriminative behavior against an outgroup. These conditions were
			satisfied in the experimental design. In the first series of
			experiements, it was found that the subjects favoured their own group in
			the distribution of real rewards and penalties in a situation in which
			nothing but the variable of fairly irrelevant classification
			distinguished between the ingroup and the outgroup. In the second series
			of experiements it was found that: 1) maximum joint profit independent
			of group membership did not affect significanly the manner in which the
			subjects divided real pecuniary rwards; 2) maximum profit for own group
			rewards did affect the distribution of rewards; 3) the clearest effect
			on the distribution of rewards was due to the subjects' attempt to
			achieve a maximum difference between the ingroup and the outgroup even
			at the price of sacrificing other 'objective' advantages. The design and
			results of the study are theoretically discussed within the framework of
			social norms and expectations and particiularly in relation to a
			'generic' norm of outgroup behavior prevalent in some societies.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Interpersonal dynamics in a simulated prison</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Zimbardo, PG</rsc>
			<rsc>Haney, Craig</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1973</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Social Identity Theory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>ABSTRACT NOT FOUND</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>The five factor model of personality</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>McCrae, RR</rsc>
			<rsc>Costa, PT</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1999</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Personality</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>N/A</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>The attribution of attitudes [FAE]</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Jones, Edward E</rsc>
			<rsc>Harris, Victor A</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1967</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Attribution errors</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Three experiments were conducted within the framework of
			correspondent inference theory. In each of the experiments the
			subjects were instructed to estimate the “true” attitude of a target
			person after having either read or listened to a speech by him
			expressing opinions on a controversial topic. Independent variables
			included position of speech (pro, anti, or equivocal), choice of
			position vs. assignment of position, and reference group of target
			person. The major hypothesis (which was confirmed with varying
			strength in all three experiments) was that choice would make a
			greater difference when there was a low prior probability of
			someone taking the position expressed in the speech. Other findings
			of interest were: (1) a tendency to attribute attitude in line with
			behavior, even in no-choice conditions; (2) increased
			inter-individual variability in conditions where low probability
			opinions were expressed in a constraining context; (3) that this
			variability was partly a function of the subjects' own attitudes on
			the issue; (4) that equivocation in no-choice conditions leads to
			the attribution that the equivocator opposes the assigned position.
			The main conclusion suggested is that perceivers do take account of
			prior probabilities and situational constraints when attributing
			private attitude, but perhaps do not weight these factors as heavily
			as would be expected by a rational analysis.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>The chameleon effect: the perception-behavior link and social interaction</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Chartrand, Tanya L</rsc>
			<rsc>Bargh, John A</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1999</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural level of analysis</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			The chameleon effect refers to nonconscious mimicry of the
			postures, mannerisms, facial expressions, and other behaviors of
			one's interaction partners, such that one's behavior passively and
			unintentionally changes to match that of others in one's current
			social environment. The authors suggest that the mechanism involved
			is the perception–behavior link, the recently documented finding
			(e.g., J. A. Bargh, M. Chen, &amp; L Burrows, 1996) that the mere
			perception of another's behavior automatically increases the
			likelihood of engaging in that behavior oneself. Experiment 1 showed
			that the motor behavior of participants unintentionally matched that
			of strangers with whom they worked on a task. Experiment 2 had
			confederates mimic the posture and movements of participants and
			showed that mimicry facilitates the smoothness of interactions and
			increases liking between interaction partners. Experiment 3 showed
			that dispositionally empathic individuals exhibit the chameleon
			effect to a greater extent than do other people.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Some determinates and consequences of the teacher's perception of causation</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Johnson, Thomas J</rsc>
			<rsc>Feigenbaum, Rhoada</rsc>
			<rsc>Weiby, Marcia</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1964</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Attribution errors</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			In a simulated teaching situation 80 Ss taught arithmetic
			concepts to fictitious "students" who then performed high
			(Student A) or low (Student B) on a related task. The cause of this
			performance was perceived as internal to the students; and positive
			characteristics were attributed to A, negative to B. Sentiments
			expressed for A were different from B. Ss were then informed that
			A's "real" characteristics were positive and that B's
			characteristics were either positive (equivalent to A) or negative.
			They presented a second concept on which A again performed high and
			B performed either high or low. When B's second performance was
			high, Ss tended to perceive themselves as responsible for the
			improvement, but perceived B as responsible when his performance
			remained low. There was also less difference between the sentiments
			expressed for A and B when B improved.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Is there a universal need for positive self-regard?</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Heine, Steven J</rsc>
			<rsc>Lehman, Darrin R</rsc>
			<rsc>Markus, Hazel Rose</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1999</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Culture</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			It is assumed that people seek positive self-regard; that is,
			they are motivated to possess, enhance, and maintain positive
			self-views. The cross-cultural generalizability of such motivations
			was addressed by examining Japanese culture. Anthropological,
			sociological, and psychological analyses revealed that many elements
			of Japanese culture are incongruent with such motivations. Moreover,
			the empirical literature provides scant evidence for a need for
			positive self-regard among Japanese and indicates that a
			self-critical focus is more characteristic of Japanese. It is argued
			that the need for self-regard must be culturally variant because the
			constructions of self and regard themselves differ across cultures.
			The need for positive self-regard, as it is currently conceptualized,
			is not a universal, but rather is rooted in significant aspects of
			North American culture. Conventional interpretations of positive
			self-regard are too narrow to encompass the Japanese experience.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>On the belief that arthritis pain is related to the weather</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Redelmeier, DA</rsc>
			<rsc>Tversky, A</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1995</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural level of analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Attribution errors</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			There is a widespread and strongly held belief that arthritis
			pain is influenced by the weather; however, scientific studies have
			found no consistent association. We hypothesize that this belief
			results, in part at least, from people's tendency to perceive
			patterns where none exist. We studied patients (n = 18) for more
			than I year and found no statistically significant associations
			between their arthritis pain and the weather conditions implicated
			by each individual. We also found that college students (n = 97)
			tend to perceive correlations between uncorrelated random sequences.
			This departure of people's intuitive notion of association from the
			statistical concept of association, we suggest, contributes to the
			belief that arthritis pain is influenced by the weather.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Influence of models' reinforcement contingencies on the acquisition of the imitative responses</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Bandura, Albert</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1965</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Social learning theory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			In order to test the hypothesis that reinforcements
			administered to a model influence the performance but not the
			acquisition of matching responses, groups of children observed an
			aggressive film-mediated model either rewarded, punished, or left
			without consequences. A postexposure test revealed that response
			consequences to the model had produced differential amounts of
			imitative behavior. Children in the model-punished condition
			performed signifcantly fewer matching responses than children in
			both the model-rewarded and the no-consequences groups. Children in
			all 3 treatment conditions were then offered attractive reinforcers
			contingent on their reproducing the model's aggressive responses.
			The introduction of positive incentives completely wiped out the
			previously observed performance differences, revealing an
			equivalent amount of learning among children in the model-rewarded,
			model-punished, and the no-consequences conditions.
		 </abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Rational imitation in preverbal infants</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Gergely, György</rsc>
			<rsc>Bekkering, Harold</rsc>
			<rsc>Király, Ildikó</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2002</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Social learning theory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Babies may opt for a simpler way to turn on a light after
			watching an adult do it. Here we show that if an adult demonstrates
			a new way to execute a task to a group of infants aged 14 months,
			the children will use this action to achieve the same goal only if
			they consider it to be the most rational alternative. Our results
			indicate that imitation of goal-directed action by preverbal infants
			is a selective, interpretative process, rather than a simple
			re-enactment of the means used by a demonstrator, as was previously
			thought.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Opinions and Social Pressure</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Asch, Solomon E</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1955</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Conformity</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>N/A</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Norm formation and conformity in an ambiguous situation</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Sherif, M</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1935</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Conformity</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			This monograph reports a study of differential responses
			determined by social factors when the individuals face the same
			stimulus situation. Individuals of different cultures may react in
			widely different ways to the same stimulus situation; these
			differences are due to differences of subjective norms or frames of
			reference. In the range experiments the subjects estimated the
			extent of movement. When the objective scale was missing, the
			individual built up his own reference point or norm. When these
			individuals are later put in a group situation their points of
			reference converge toward a common norm. Stereotypes, fads,
			traditions, fashions, customs, and attitudes are psychologically
			cases of establishment of socially determined norms and values
			serving as frames of reference.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Compliance without pressure: The foot-in-the-door technique</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Freedman, Jonathan L</rsc>
			<rsc>Fraser, Scott C</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1966</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Compliance</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			2 experiments were conducted to test the proposition that once
			someone has agreed to a small request he is more likely to comply
			with a larger request. Exp. I demonstrated this effect when the same
			person made both requests; Exp. II extended this to the situation in
			which different people made the 2 requests. Several experimental
			groups were run in an effort to explain these results, and possible
			explanations are discussed.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Raising the price of agreement: Public commitment and the lowball compliance procedure</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Burger, Jerry M</rsc>
			<rsc>Cornelius, Tara</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2003</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Compliance</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Three studies examined the effect on compliance when a
			requester raises the price of the request. Participants in
			Experiment 1 were told that they would receive a free coffee mug for
			donating money to a fundraiser but were interrupted before they
			could respond and were told that the fundraisers were out of mugs.
			These participants were less likely to donate money than a group
			told nothing about the mugs. Experiments 2 and 3 compared this
			interruption procedure with the lowball procedure, which also uses a
			small-to-large price progression. The results from these two studies
			indicate that allowing people to respond to the initial price is
			critical for producing the lowball effect. Without a statement of
			public commitment, the small-to-large price progression led to a
			decrease rather than an increase in compliance relative to a control
			group.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Consistency-based compliance across cultures</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Petrova, Petia K</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2007</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Compliance</fcs>
			<fcs>Culture</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			A field study investigated cross-cultural differences in
			choice-congruent behavior and its impact on compliance. U.S. and
			Asian participants received a request to complete an online survey
			and a month later they were approached with a larger, related
			request. Compliance with the initial request had a stronger impact
			on subsequent compliance among the U.S. participants than among the
			Asian participants. Despite their lower rate of compliance with the
			initial request, the U.S. participants who chose to comply were more
			likely than their Asian counterparts to agree to the subsequent
			request. Further analyses revealed that this effect was driven by
			differences in the individualistic/collectivistic orientation of the
			participants from the two cultures. Within both cultures, the more
			individualistic participants showed stronger consistency with their
			earlier compliance than the more collectivistically oriented
			participants.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Culture and conformity: A meta-analysis of studies using Asch's (1952b, 1956) line judgment task</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Bond, Rod</rsc>
			<rsc>Smith, Peter B</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1996</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Conformity</fcs>
			<fcs>Culture</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			A meta-analysis of conformity studies using an Asch-type line
			judgment task (1952, 1956) was conducted to investigate whether the
			level of conformity has changed over time and whether it is related
			cross-culturally to individualism–collectivism. The literature
			search produced 133 studies drawn from 17 countries. An analysis of
			US studies found that conformity has declined since the 1950s.
			Results from 3 surveys were used to assess a country's
			individualism–collectivism, and for each survey the measures were
			found to be significantly related to conformity. Collectivist
			countries tended to show higher levels of conformity than
			individualist countries. Conformity research must attend more to
			cultural variables and to their role in the processes involved in
			social influence.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Cultural differences in consumer impatience</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Chen, Haipeng A</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2005</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Culture</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			In this article, the authors examine cross-cultural variations
			in how people discount the future. Specifically, they predict that
			people from Western cultures are relatively less patient and
			therefore discount the future to a greater degree than do people
			from Eastern cultures, and thus Westerners value immediate
			consumption relatively more. Furthermore, on the basis of regulatory
			focus theory, the authors predict that when Easterners are faced
			with the threat of a delay in receiving a product (i.e., a
			prevention loss), they are more impatient, whereas when Westerners
			are faced with the threat of not being able to enjoy a product early
			(i.e., a promotion loss), their impatience increases. This enhanced
			impatience manifests in preference for expedited consumption of a
			product purchased online in two studies. In both studies, the
			authors used a priming methodology on “bicultural” Singaporean
			participants; the results support the predictions. In the second
			study, they also found evidence in support of the process-based
			explanation for the interaction between culture and message framing.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>The pace of life in 31 countries</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Robert V. Levine</rsc>
			<rsc>Ara Norenzayen</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1999</year>
		<focus>
			<fsc>Sociocultural Level of Analysis</fsc>
			<fcs>Culture</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			This study compared the pace of life in large cities from 31
			countries around the world. Three indicators of pace of life were
			observed: average walking speed in downtown locations, the speed
			with which postal clerks completed a simple request (work speed),
			and the accuracy of public clocks. Overall, pace of life was fastest
			in Japan and the countries of Western Europe and was slowest in
			economically undeveloped countries. The pace was significantly
			faster in colder climates, economically productive countries, and in
			individualistic cultures. Faster places also tended to have higher
			rates of death from coronary heart disease, higher smoking rates,
			and greater subjective well-being. Discussion focuses on how the
			pace of life is intertwined with the social-psychological and
			community characteristics of a culture, and the central role of pace
			of life in defining the personality of a place and its people.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Two storage mechanisms in free recall</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Glanzer, Murray</rsc>
			<rsc>Cunitz, Anita</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1966</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Memory</fcs>
			<fcs>Multistore memory model</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Two experiments were carried out to test the hypothesis that the
			bimodal serial position curve in free recall is produced by output
			from two storage mechanisms--short-term	and long-term. Experimental
			operations were applied that were predicted to have a distinct
			effect on each of these mechanisms, and the changes in the serial
			position curve were observed. In the first experiment, presentation
			rate and repetition of individual words were varied in order to
			affect long-term storage and thereby affect the beginning sections
			of the serial position curve. Presentation rate has the predicted
			effect of differentially raising the beginning section of the
			serial position curve. It does not affect the end section.
			Repetition, however, did not have any effect that could not be
			ascribed to presentation rate. It could not, therefore, be used to
			demonstrate independently the predicted differential effect. In the
			second experiment, delay between end of	list and recall was varied
			in order to affect short-term storage and, thereby, the end	section
			of the serial position curve. The predicted effect was clearly
			demonstrated. The results make it possible to systematize a number
			of findings in the literature.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>The effect of schemas on memory</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Bartlett, Frederic</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1932</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Schema theory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>ABSTRACT NOT FOUND</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Recall of previously unrecallable information following a shift in perspective</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Anderson, Richard C</rsc>
			<rsc>Pichert, James W</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1978</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Schema theory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			College undergraduates read a story about two boys playing hooky
			from school from the perspective of either a burglar or a person
			interested in buying a home. After recalling the story once,
			subjects were directed to shift perspectives and then recall the
			story again. In two experiments, subjects produced on the second
			recall significantly more information important to the second
			perspective that had been unimportant to the first. They also
			recalled less information unimportant to the second perspective
			which had been important to the first. These data clearly show the
			operation of retrieval processes independent from encoding
			processes. An analysis of interview protocols suggested that the
			instruction to take a new perspective led subjects to invoke a
			schema that provided implicit cues for different categories of
			story information.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Contextual prerequisites for understanding: Some investigations of comprehension and recall</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Bransford, John D</rsc>
			<rsc>Johnson, Marcia K</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1978</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Schema theory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			The present paper presents a series of studies showing that
			relevant contextual knowledge is a prerequisite for comprehending
			prose passages. Four studies are reported, each demonstrating
			increased comprehension ratings and recall scores when Ss were
			supplied with appropriate information before they heard test
			passages. Supplying Ss with the same information subsequent to the
			passages produced much lower comprehension ratings and recall
			scores. Various explanations of the results are considered, and the
			role of topics in activating cognitive contexts is discussed.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Memory for a staged criminal event witnessed live and on video</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Ihleback, C</rsc>
			<rsc>Løve, T</rsc>
			<rsc>Eilertsen, DE</rsc>
			<rsc>Magnussen, S</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2003</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Witness reliability</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Memory for a staged robbery was tested in two groups of participants
			witnessing the event either live (n = 62) or on video (n = 64).
			Immediately after the event participants filled out a questionnaire
			probing memory with emphasis on the timing of the event and robber
			characteristics. The results showed that participants who watched a
			video recording of the event reported more details and with a higher
			accuracy than participants who were present on the scene, but the
			pattern of memory errors were similar in the two conditions. It is
			concluded that laboratory experiments may overestimate the memory of
			eyewitnesses but are otherwise able to simulate essential aspects of
			memory performance in naturalistic contexts.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>A case study of eyewitness memory of a crime</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Yuille, John C</rsc>
			<rsc>Cutshall, Judith L</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1986</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Witness reliability</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			21 witnesses observed a shooting incident in which 1 person
			was killed and a 2nd seriously wounded. The incident took place on a
			major thoroughfare in midafternoon. All of the witnesses were
			interviewed by the investigating police, and 13 witnesses
			(aged 15–32 yrs) agreed to a research interview 4–5 mo after the
			event. In the present study, the eyewitness accounts provided in
			both the police and research interviews were analyzed. The witnesses
			were highly accurate in their accounts, and there was little change
			in amount or accuracy of recall over 5 mo. However, some aspects of
			color memory and age, height, and weight estimations were found to
			be erroneous. The eyewitnesses resisted leading questions, and their
			stress levels at the time of the event appeared to have no negative
			effects on subsequent memory. The results differ from the pattern of
			many laboratory studies of eyewitness memory (i.e., in the degree to
			which the witnesses in the present study were actively involved in
			the event) and point to the need for field research of this type to
			evaluate the generalizability of laboratory experiments.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Flashbulb memories</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Brown, Roger</rsc>
			<rsc>Kulik, James</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1977</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Flashbulb memory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Flashbulb Memories are memories for the circumstances in which one
			first learned of a very surprising and consequential (or emotionally
			arousing) event. Hearing the news that President John Kennedy had
			been shot is the prototype case. Almost everyone can remember, with
			an almost perceptual clarity, where he was when he heard, what he
			was doing at the time, who told him, what was the immediate
			aftermath, how he felt about it, and also one or more totally
			idiosyncratic and often trivial concomitants. The present paper
			reports a questionnaire inquiry into the determinants of such
			memories by asking about other assassinations, highly newsworthy
			events, and personally significant events. It is shown that while
			the Kennedy assassination created an extraordinarily powerful and
			widely shared flashbulb memory, it is not the only event that has
			created such memories. The principal two determinants appear to be
			a high level of surprise, a high level of consequentiality, or
			perhaps emotional arousal (assessed by both rating scales and ethnic
			group membership). If these two variables do not attain sufficiently
			high levels, no flashbulb memory occurs. If they do attain high
			levels, they seem, most directly, to affect the frequency of
			rehearsal, covert and overt, which, in turn, affects the degree of
			elaboration in the narrative of the memory that can be elicited
			experimentally. Parallels are made explicit between the behavioral
			theory and a less elaborated, speculative neuro-physiological theory
			of which R. B. Livingston (1967) is the proponent Finally, an
			argument is made that a permanent memory for incidental concomitants
			of a surprising and consequential (in the sense of biologically
			significant) event would have high selection value and so could
			account for the evolution of an innate base for such a memory
			mechanism.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Phantom flashbulbs: False recollections of hearing the news about Challenger</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Neisser, Ulric</rsc>
			<rsc>Harsch, Nicole</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1992</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Flashbulb memory</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			report the results of a longitudinal study of memory for [the
			Space Shuttle Challenger explosion] / the morning after the
			explosion, Neisser collected questionnaires from . . . [44]
			psychology students about how they had heard the news / after a
			lapse of nearly 3 years, the same informants were asked the same
			questions again / the most noteworthy outcome of this study is that
			over 40% of the informants were clearly inconsistent across the two
			occasions / these results bring the accuracy of flashbulb memories
			into question
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name> Experimental reduction of stress based on ego-defense theory</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Speisman, Joseph C</rsc>
			<rsc>Lazarus, Richard S</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1964</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Emotions</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Previous research had shown that a silent film showing
			primitive adolescent "subincision" rites produced marked stress
			reactions. 3 sound tracks were created for the film and compared
			in impact with the silent version. 1, called the trauma track,
			pointed up the threatening aspect of the film. The other 2, based
			upon the theory of ego defense, were designed to encourage defensive
			interpretations of the film's contents so as to reduce threat. One
			consisted of denial and reaction formation statements about the
			film, the other was based on intellectualization. The trauma track
			increased evidences of stress response especially with respect to
			continuous recordings of skin conductance during the film. The
			defensive sound tracks reduced skin conductance evidence of stress
			response. The effectiveness of the defensive sound tracks interacted
			with the 2 S groups. Intellectualization was effective for the
			students and may have been also for the air executives, but denial
			was not as effective, at least for the student group. The findings
			supported the importance of the process of cognitive appraisal of
			threat in producing stress reactions, permitting the conclusion that
			the same visual stimulus varies in the amount of stress produced
			depending upon the nature of the cognitive appraisal the person
			makes regarding its significance for him.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Patterns of emotion-specific appraisal, coping, and cardiovascular reactivity during an ongoing emotional episode</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Herrald, Mary M</rsc>
			<rsc>Tomaka, Joe</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2002</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Emotions</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			The authors examined emotion-specific patterns of appraisal,
			coping, and cardiovascular reactivity during real ongoing emotional
			episodes. In this study, 109 participants performed a neutral
			opinion-expression task, where a confederate elicited anger, shame,
			or pride using verbal and nonverbal behavior. The authors assessed
			cognitive appraisals, emotional reactions, coping, outcomes (state
			self-esteem and outcome satisfaction), and cardiovascular reactivity.
			Results indicated substantial and theoretically consistent
			differences between the 3 emotions (and differences from a
			nonemotion condition) for cognitive appraisals, self-reported coping,
			behavioral coping, self-esteem, and cardiovascular reactivity. The
			results are discussed in relation to their implications for emotion
			theory and for psychological and physical health. Overall, the
			results suggest that researchers can study emotion-related issues
			using authentic emotional reactions.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Masked presentations of emotional facial expressions modulate amygdala activity without explicit Knowledge</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Whalen, Paul J</rsc>
			<rsc>Rauch, Scott L</rsc>
			<rsc>Etcoff, Nancy L</rsc>
			<rsc>McInerney, Sean C</rsc>
			<rsc>Lee, Michael B</rsc>
			<rsc>Jenike, Michael A</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1998</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Cognitive Level of Analysis</fcs>
			<fcs>Emotions</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) of the human
			brain was used to study whether the amygdala is activated in
			response to emotional stimuli, even in the absence of explicit
			knowledge that such stimuli were presented. Pictures of human faces
			bearing fearful or happy expressions were presented to 10 normal,
			healthy subjects by using a backward masking procedure that resulted
			in 8 of 10 subjects reporting that they had not seen these facial
			expressions. The backward masking procedure consisted of 33 msec
			presentations of fearful or happy facial expressions, their offset
			coincident with the onset of 167 msec presentations of neutral
			facial expressions. Although subjects reported seeing only neutral
			faces, blood oxygen level-dependent (BOLD) fMRI signal in the
			amygdala was significantly higher during viewing of masked fearful
			faces than during the viewing of masked happy faces. This difference
			was composed of significant signal increases in the amygdala to
			masked fearful faces as well as significant signal decreases to
			masked happy faces, consistent with the notion that the level of
			amygdala activation is affected differentially by the emotional
			valence of external stimuli. In addition, these facial expressions
			activated the sublenticular substantia innominata (SI), where signal
			increases were observed to both fearful and happy faces—suggesting a
			spatial dissociation of territories that respond to emotional
			valence versus salience or arousal value. This study, using fMRI in
			conjunction with masked stimulus presentations, represents an
			initial step toward determining the role of the amygdala in
			nonconscious processing.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<!--Year 1 end-->
	<frame>
		<name>Reliability of DSM-IV anxiety and mood disorders: Implications for the classification of emotional disorders</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Brown, Timothy A</rsc>
			<rsc>DiNardo, Peter A</rsc>
			<rsc>Lehman, Cassandra L</rsc>
			<rsc>Laura, Campbell A</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2001</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Abnormal Psychology</fcs>
			<fcs>Diagnostic reliability</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			The reliability of current and lifetime Diagnostic and Statistical
			Manual of Mental Disorders (4th ed.; DSM-IV; American Psychiatric
			Association, 1994) anxiety and mood disorders was examined in 362
			outpatients who underwent 2 independent administrations of the
			Anxiety Disorders Interview Schedule for DSM-IV: Lifetime version
			(ADIS-IV–L). Good to excellent reliability was obtained for the
			majority of DSM-IV categories. For many disorders, a common source
			of unreliability was disagreements on whether constituent symptoms
			were sufficient in number, severity, or duration to meet DSM-IV
			diagnostic criteria. These analyses also highlighted potential
			boundary problems for some disorders (e.g., generalized anxiety
			disorder and major depressive disorder). Analyses of ADIS-IV–L
			clinical ratings (0–8 scales) indicated favorable interrater
			agreement for the dimensional features of DSM-IV anxiety and mood
			disorders. The findings are discussed in regard to their
			implications for the classification of emotional disorders.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Children into DSM don't go: A comparison of classification systems for eating disorders in childhood and early adolescence</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Nicholls, Dasha</rsc>
			<rsc>Chater, Rachel</rsc>
			<rsc>Lask, Bryan</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1999</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Abnormal Psychology</fcs>
			<fcs>Diagnostic reliability</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Objective: To evaluate the reliability of diagnostic classification
			systems for eating disorders when applied to children and young
			adolescents. Method: Eighty-one patients were randomly selected from
			a population of 226 children (age 7-16) presentig with eating
			difficulties to a specialist clinic. Diagnoses were assigned
			according to three classification systems: the 10th edition of the
			International Classification of Diseases (ICD 10), the 4th edition
			of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders
			(DSM-IV), and Great Ormond Street (GOS) criteria. Ratings were
			performed by two clinicians blind to the diagnosis of the other.
			Results: Interrater reliablity values (kappa) for the three systems
			were 0.357 (ICD 10), 0.636 (DSM-IV), and 0.879 (GOD). using DSM
			criteria, more than 50% of children were classified as eating
			disorder not otherwise classified (EDNOS) or could not be
			classified. Discussion: DSM-IV and ICD 10 criteria are of little
			value in the classification of the eating difficulties of children.
			The GOS criteria, which were developed for this age range, are more
			reliable. The classification of eating disorders in childhood needs
			reevaluation.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Labelling theory</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Caetano</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>1973</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Abnormal Psychology</fcs>
			<fcs>Diagnostic ethics</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>ABSTRACT NOT FOUND</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>A swedish national twin study of lifetime major depression</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Kendler, Kenneth S</rsc>
			<rsc>Gatz, Margaret</rsc>
			<rsc>Gardner, Charles O</rsc>
			<rsc>Pedersen, Nancy L</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2006</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Abnormal psychology</fcs>
			<fcs>Depression</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Sweden has, as a whole nation, the oldest continuous
			population register of births, including twin and higher multiple
			maternities, starting in the 17th century. Until the 1920s, the
			rates of multiple maternities in Sweden were among the highest known
			among Europeans. Strong secular and regional fluctuations were
			noted. Some of the eastern counties showed especially marked
			decreasing trends. The twinning rate had no clear associations
			with the anthropometric and serological data. In this paper we study
			the temporal and regional variations of the twinning rate in the 25
			counties of Sweden from 1751 to 1960. Different statistical methods
			were applied in order to test the hypothesis that, irrespective of
			the initial levels, the twinning rates for the counties converge
			towards a common low level. We present and interpret a geometrical
			model for the trends of the regional twinning rates. We also analyze
			the regional heterogeneity using the ranges and the coefficients of
			variation of the regional twinning rates. All the methods gave
			consistent results, supporting our convergence hypothesis that the
			regional differences in the twinning rate are gradually
			disappearing. In addition, this study supports our earlier findings
			that the regional heterogeneity cannot be explained by differences
			in the distribution of maternal age and parity. We suggest that the
			convergence may be caused by increased urbanization and
			industrialization and by the increased interregional migration of
			citizens as a consequence of better communications, which lead to
			the breaking up of isolates and decreased endogamy.</abstract>
	</frame>
	<frame>
		<name>Correlation between Cortisol and Negative Life Events</name>
		<researchers>
			<rsc>Cutuli, JJ</rsc>
			<rsc>Wilk, Kristen L</rsc>
			<rsc>Herbers, Janette E</rsc>
			<rsc>Gunnar, Megan R</rsc>
			<rsc>Masten, Ann S</rsc>
		</researchers>
		<year>2010</year>
		<focus>
			<fcs>Abnormal Psychology</fcs>
			<fcs>Depression</fcs>
		</focus>
		<abstract>
			Homelessness represents a context of extreme poverty and risk for
			child development. This study compared the relative influence of two
			classes of risk in the context of homelessness. Levels of
			socioeconomic resource-related risk and negative lifetime events
			were examined with respect to morning cortisol levels and cortisol
			response to a set of cognitive tasks. Participants were 66 children
			between the ages of 4 and 7 years staying in an emergency shelter
			for families. Adversities largely reflecting family level negative
			life events predicted higher levels of morning cortisol and
			differences in initial level and change over the course of the
			session of cognitive tasks. In contrast, a socioeconomic cumulative
			risk score was not associated with morning or session-related
			differences in cortisol.
		</abstract>
	</frame>
</FrameList>
